# Matthew Harvey Brandenburgh

3912 Timbalier Dr., Columbus, GA 31907 phone: 706-442-0625 mhbrandenburgh@gmail.com

# ABOUT ME

I am a creative and focused team player with past years of experience in the filmmaking world and new to computer programming. I also bring a strong mathematical and computational background through my education and 15+ years of experience as a math and physics tutor.

# **TECH STACK**

Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Tailwinds, Express.js, Node, SQL, MySQL2, Sequelize, Mongo, Mongoose, Mongo Compass, GraphQL, Adobe Premiere (video editing)

### **DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

# Rhythm Room

A full MERN-stack website where users can create their own playlists, like and comment on others'
playlists, and connect their account to spotify to listen to the music.

#### **Auction Plaza**

- An auction website that lets users create an account, list items for sale, and bid on posted items.
- Used node.js, express.js, and SQL, and CSS Tailwinds for design

# Workplace Dynamic Scheduler

• A vanilla JavaScript application that accepts user inputs and generates a calendar display of possible employee schedules, using local storage

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Tutor, self-employed, September 2005-present

- Aided students from middle school through graduate school primarily in math and physics
- Maintained a 4.9-star rating out of 5 on listing website WyzAnt.com

Director/Editor, "Steve Forbes on Achievement" video series, June 2017-August 2020

- Helped coordinate and shoot a video series about entrepreneurs featuring Steve Forbes, then edited into a finished product incorporating archival footage and photos
- Additional duties included extensive archival research

# Freelance Director/Director of Photography/Editor, September 2016-December 2020

- Producing videos for hire under the auspices of my production company, Brandenburgh Media, LLC
- Projects included a music video, numerous commercials and corporate videos for Spectrum Cable in New York

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Physics and Mathematics, University of Georgia, May 2009

Full Stack Flex Coding Bootcamp, Georgia Tech, March 2023